如果我们不能阻止虫子，我们的第二道防线
Now if we can't prevent bugs, our second defense
试图将它们本地化到程序的一小部分，
is to try to localize them to a small part of the program,
所以我们不必找太难
so we don't have to look too hard to find
错误的原因。
the cause of the bug.
当本地化为单个方法或小模块时，
When localized to a single method or a small module,
只需研究程序文本就可以发现错误。
bugs may be found simply by studying the program text.
现在我们已经谈到了快速失败。
Now we've already talked about failing fast.
这就意味着我们观察到了先前的问题。
That means that the earlier problem is observed.
越接近其原因，就越容易修复。
The closer to its cause, the easier it's going to be to fix.
在本节中，我们将讨论一个[听不见的]
In this section, we're going to talk about a [INAUDIBLE]
称为断言。
called assertions.
让我们从一个简单的例子开始。
Let's start with a simple example.
所以我们有一个平方根函数。
So we have a square root function.
接受单双参数，并返回
Takes in the single double argument, and returns
双重侮辱。需要这个论证
a double insult. Requires that argument
大于或等于零，
to be greater than or equal to zero,
否则，我们就不会
because otherwise, we're not going to be
能够计算平方根。
able to compute a square root.
它返回x的平方根的近似值。
And it returns an approximation of the square root of x.
假设有人叫平方根
Now suppose somebody does call square root
用否定的论点，打破这个前提。
with a negative argument, breaking this precondition.
那么平方根的最佳行为是什么？
Then what's the best behavior for square root?
因为调用方未能满足
Since the caller has failed to satisfy the requirement that x
应该是非负的平方根
should be non-negative, square root
实际上不再受合同条款的约束。
is actually no longer bound by the terms of its contract.
所以从技术上讲，它可以随心所欲。
So it's technically free to do whatever it wants.
它可以返回任意值。
It could return an arbitrary value.
它可以进入一个无限循环，永远不会返回。
It could enter an infinite loop and never return.
如果它想的话，它可以让CPU熔化。
It can melt down the CPU if it wants.
因为那个错误的调用表明调用程序中有一个错误，
Since that bad call indicates a bug in the caller,
然而，最有用的行为
however, the most useful behavior
会尽早向客户指出错误
would be to point out the bug to that client as early
尽可能的。
as possible.
所以我们可以插入一个运行时断言
So we can do this by inserting a runtime assertion that
在我们开始该方法之前测试先决条件。
tests the precondition before we even start the method.
有一种方法我们可以写下这个断言。
Here's one way we might write that assertion.
换言之，如果不满足先决条件，
In other words, if the precondition is not satisfied,
我们将抛出一个例外。
we're going to throw an exception.
我们将使用的特殊例外
And the particular exception we're going to use
是Java中的一个内置错误，称为断言错误。
is a built-in one in Java called Assertion Error.
这样，呼叫者的错误的影响，
That way, the effects of the caller's bug,
在这里传递x的负值，
passing a negative value here for x,
阻止在程序中进一步传播。
are prevented from propagating further in the program.
检查这样的前提条件就是一个例子
Checking preconditions like this is an example
防御性编程。
of defensive programming.
真正的程序很少没有bug，
Real programs are rarely bug-free,
所以防御性编程提供了一种方法
so defensive programming offers a way
为了减轻这些虫子的影响，
to mitigate the effects of those bugs,
即使你不知道他们在哪里。
even if you don't know where they are.
现在定义一个程序是一种常见的做法，
Now it's a common practice to define a procedure,
甚至是语言功能
or even a language feature, for these kinds
防御性检查，通常称为断言。
of defensive checks, usually called Assert.
Assert所做的是使用一个布尔表达式
What Assert does is it takes a Boolean expression that
本质上是这样一种说法
is essentially a claim that this expression should
在程序中的这一点上是正确的。
be true at this point in the program.
如果不是真的，那么Assert将抛出一个异常
And if it's not true, then Assert will throw an exception
停止程序。
and stop the program.
尽管这种方法实际上是[？摘要？]
Although this approach actually [? abstracts ?]
远离那个断言失败时发生的事情。
away from exactly what happens when that assertion fails.
它可能会退出程序。
It might exit the program.
它可能会将事件记录在日志文件中。
It might record the event in the Log File.
它甚至可以向维护人员发送电子邮件或报告。
It might even email or report to a maintainer.
这就是包装的美
That's the beauty of just packaging
所有这些都在断言中。
all that in an Assert.
断言有额外的好处
Assertions have the added benefit
记录关于国家的假设
of documenting an assumption about the state
在那一点上的程序。
of the program at that point.
换句话说，这对人类程序员来说是可读的。
In other words, this is readable to a human programmer.
它说，在这一点上，应该永远
It says, at this point, should always
如果x大于或等于零，则为真。
be true that x is greater than or equal to zero.
与注释不同，断言实际上是可执行代码。
Unlike a comment, an assertion is actually executable code.
它在运行时执行该假设。
It enforces that assumption at run time.
现在在Java中，运行时断言实际上是一个内置的特性
Now in Java, runtime assertions are actually a built-in feature
关于语言。
of the language.
这不是Java中的函数调用。
This is not a function call in Java.
这实际上是一个声明。
It's actually a statement.
Assert语句的最简单形式
The simplest form of the Assert statement
只需要一个布尔表达式，正如上面所示。
just takes a Boolean expression, exactly as shown above.
注意我们不需要给它加括号。
Notice we don't need to give parentheses to it.
从这个意义上讲，它有点像一个return语句。
It's kind of like a return statement in that sense.
如果布尔表达式
And it throws an assertion error if the Boolean expression
计算结果为false。
evaluates to false.
现在，Java中的Assert语句也可以
Now an Assert statement in Java may also
有一个描述表达式，通常是一个字符串，
have a description expression, which is usually a string,
也可以是基元类型或对对象的引用。
may also be a primitive type or a reference to an object.
该描述将打印在错误消息中
That description is printed in an error message
当断言失败时
when the assertion fails so it can
用于向程序员提供其他详细信息
be used to provide additional details to the programmer
关于失败的原因。
about the cause of failure.
描述跟随断言表达式，
The description follows the asserted expression,
由结肠分隔。
separated by a colon.
所以如果x等于负数，当这个断言语句是
So if x equals negative one when this assertion statement is
点击，则此断言将失败，并显示错误消息，
hit, then this assertion will fail with the error message,
x是负的，还有一个堆栈跟踪，
x is negative one, along with a stack trace,
这就是你能得到的每一个例外
which is what you get with every exception
那个[听不见的]从未被抓住。
that [INAUDIBLE] never caught.
它告诉您assert语句
It tells you where the assert statement
在您的代码和调用序列中找到
was found in your code and the sequence of calls that brought
到那一点的程序。
the program to that point.
你可以得到很多信息
That's a lot of information for you to get
开始寻找虫子。
started in finding the bug.
但是，Java断言的一个严重问题
However, a serious problem with Java assertions
默认情况下它们是关闭的。如果你只是
is that they are turned off by default. If you just
像往常一样运行程序，没有任何断言
run your program as usual, none of your assertions
将被检查。
will be checked.
它会完全跳过这一行。
It will just skip over this line entirely.
Java的设计人员做到了这一点——他们将此作为默认设置
Java's designers did this-- they made this the default
行为——因为检查断言有时
behavior-- because checking assertions can sometimes
性能昂贵。
be costly to performance.
例如，一个使用
So for example, a procedure that searches an array using
二进制搜索通常有一个先决条件
binary search typically has a precondition
在调用数组之前对其进行排序。
that the array be sorted before you call it.
断言此需求，测试
Asserting this requirement, testing
不管数组是否被排序，
whether the array actually is sorted,
需要扫描整个阵列
would require scanning through the entire array, which
会改变一个应该
would turn an operation that ought
在对数时间内运行——二进制搜索
to run in logarithmic time-- binary search
是一个对数运算
is a logarithmic operation-- to one that
需要线性时间，因为你
takes linear time, just because you're
测试数组是否实际排序。
testing whether the array actually is sorted.
现在你应该愿意，甚至是渴望，
Now you should be willing, even eager,
在测试和开发过程中支付线性成本，
to pay this linear cost during testing, during development,
因为这会让你的调试更容易
since it makes your debugging so much easier
抓住你忘了的案子
to catch that case where you forgot
在使用此二进制搜索之前对数组排序
to sort the array before using this binary search
但不是在程序发布给用户之后。
but not after the program is released to users.
但是，对于大多数应用程序--对于大多数断言，
For most applications, however-- for most assertions,
相比之下，断言并不昂贵
assertions are not expensive compared
其他代码。
to the rest of the code.
以及它们在错误检查中提供的好处
And the benefit they provide in bug checking
在性能上通常值得这么小的成本。
is often worth that small cost in performance.
所以在Java中，必须显式地启用断言，
So in Java, you have to enable assertions explicitly,
绕过dash EA，它代表启用断言
bypassing dash EA, which stands for Enable Assertions
到Java虚拟机。
to the Java virtual machine.
在Eclipse中，您可以启用断言
In Eclipse, you can enable assertions
通过运行，运行配置，
by going to Run, Run Configurations,
[? 论据？]，并将EA放入VM Arguments框中。
[? Arguments ?], and putting EA in the VM Arguments Box.
实际上，最好默认启用它们
In fact, it's best to enable them by default
转到Preferences Java Installed[？JREs？]，编辑，
by going to Preferences Java Installed [? JREs ?], Edit,
默认值，VM参数。
Default, VM Arguments.
我们建议你这样做
And that's what we recommend you do
当你在本课程中设置习题集时。
when you set up for the problem sets in this course.
转变主张总是个好主意
It's always a good idea to have assertions turned
当你运行JUnit测试时，
on when you're running JUnit tests,
因为这样你就知道你正处于发展的境地。
because then you know you're in a development situation.
表现不应该是正确的。
Performance shouldn't matter as much as getting it right.
所以您可以编写一个JUnit测试来确保
So you can write a JUnit test that ensures
断言已启用。
that assertions are enabled.
它所做的是创建一个断言，该断言应该始终
What this does is it creates an assertion that should always
失败。
fail.
这将始终引发断言错误。
This should always throw an assertion error.
测试希望它抛出断言错误。
And the test expects that it will throw an assertion error.
所以如果断言碰巧被开启，
So if assertions happen to be turned on,
这次考试会通过的，因为
this test is going to pass, because it's
将正确抛出断言错误。
going to correctly throw an assertion error.
如果断言被关闭，则
If assertions are turned off, it's
将愉快地流过这个断言语句。
going to just flow happily past this assertion statement.
测试将不会看到断言错误
And the test will not see the assertion error
它期待的。
that it's expecting.
注意，Java assert语句
Note that the Java assert statement
是一种不同于JUnit方法的机制，
is a different mechanism than the JUnit method,
断言为真，断言等于，等等。
assert true, assert equals, et cetera.
现在它们都断言一个关于代码的谓词，
Now they all assert a predicate about your code,
但它们是为在不同的环境中使用而设计的。
but they're designed for use in different contexts.
应该使用assert语句
The assert statement should be used
防御检查的实现代码中
in implementation code for defensive checks
在实现中。
inside the implementation.
JUnit资产应该只在JUnit测试中使用
The JUnit assertment should be used only in JUnit tests
检查测试结果。
to check the results of a test.
现在assert语句不能在没有破折号EA的情况下运行
Now the assert statements don't run without that dash EA
争论。
argument.
但是JUnit断言方法将始终运行。
But the JUnit assert methods will always run.
有些事情你应该
There is some things that you should
在实现中断言。
assert in your implementations.
坚持先决条件很好，
It's great to assert preconditions,
就像我们在上面看到的平方根。
like we saw for square root above.
很好的证明了后置条件，
It's great to assert post-conditions,
返回值的要求。
the requirements on return values.
这种断言有时
This kind of assertion is sometimes
叫自我检查。
called the self-check.
例如，平方根法
For example, the square root method
可能会把结果平方来检查
might square its result to check that it is actually
相当接近x并断言这是真的。
reasonably close to x and assert that that's true.
如果条件或开关没有
If a conditional or switch does not
把所有可能的案子都盖上
cover all the possible cases, it's
使用断言的良好实践
a good practice to use an assertion
阻止非法案件。
to block the illegal cases.
此默认子句中的断言[？有？]
The assertion in this default clause [? has ?]
断言val必须是
the effect of asserting that val must be one
五个瓦尔[听不见]。
of the five val [INAUDIBLE].
现在您应该何时插入这些运行时断言？
Now when should you insert these runtime assertions?
你应该什么时候将它们添加到代码中？
When should you add them to your code?
好吧，你应该把它们加上去
Well, you should go ahead and add them
因为你在写代码，而不是事后，因为
as you're writing the code, not after the fact, because it's
在你写代码的时候
while you are writing the code that you have
这些重要的不变量，这些重要的性质
these important invariants, these important properties that
一定是真的，在你脑子里。
must be true, in your head.
如果你推迟写断言，
If you postpone writing the assertions,
你不太可能这么做。
you're less likely to do it.
你可能会忘记一些重要的不变量。
And you're liable to forget some important invariants.
现在运行时演示不是免费的。
Now runtime demonstrations are not free.
它们会使代码混乱，因此必须谨慎使用。
They can clutter the code, so they must be used judiciously.
你应该避免琐碎的断言，
You should avoid trivial assertions,
就像你要避免无信息的评论一样。
just as you would avoid uninformative comments.
例如，如果你刚给y加1到x，
For example, if you just assigned y plus 1 to x,
根本没有理由断言x现在是
there is no reason at all to assert that x is now
等于y加1。
equal to y plus 1.
它只是在编译器中发现错误
It just finds bugs in the compiler
在Java虚拟机中，[？哪些是？]组件
in the Java virtual machine, [? which are ?] components
你应该信任他们直到你有充分的理由怀疑他们。
that you should trust until you have good reason to doubt them.
如果断言在其本地上下文中是显而易见的，
If an assertion is obvious from its local context,
别说了，就像我们在评论中说的那样。
leave it out, just like we've said with comments.
现在不要使用断言来测试外部条件
Now never use assertions to test conditions that are external
[? 然后呢？]对你的程序来说，就是文件的存在，
[? and ?] to your program, which is the existence of files,
网络的可用性、正确性
the availability of the network, correctness
由人类用户输入的输入。
of input typed by a human user.
断言应该测试程序的内部状态
Assertions should test the internal state of your program
以确保它在其规范的范围内。
to ensure that it's within the bounds of its specification.
当断言失败时，它指示
When an assertion fails, it indicates
从某种意义上说，程序已经出轨了，
that the program has run off the rails, in some sense,
进入一种不能正常工作的状态。
into a state in which it was not designed to function properly.
断言失败应指示错误。
Assertion failure should indicate bugs.
外部故障不是bug。
External failures are not bugs.
你不能改变你的程序
There is no change you can make to your program
比如说，这会提前阻止，
in advance that will prevent, for example,
网络不会崩溃。
the network from going down.
应处理外部故障
External failures should be handled
而是使用异常。
using exceptions instead.
现在有许多断言和机制
Now many assertion and mechanisms
它们的设计使得断言
are designed so that assertions are
仅在测试和调试期间执行
executed only during testing and debugging
当程序发布给用户时关闭，
and turned off when program is released to users,
正如我们在上面看到的。
as we saw above.
Java的assert语句的行为是这样的。
Java's assert statement behaves this way.
由于断言有时可能被禁用，
Since assertions may be disabled sometimes,
程序的正确性永远不应该
the correctness of your program should never
取决于断言表达式是否
depend on whether or not the assertion expressions
被处决。
are executed.
尤其是断言表达式
In particular, asserted expressions
不应该有副作用。
should not have side effects.
例如，如果要断言删除了一个元素
For example, if you want to assert that an element removed
从列表中找到的列表中
from a list that's actually found in the list, that's
列表点删除返回值--
what list dot remove returns as its return value--
一个布尔值，它表示，x实际上在那里，
a Boolean value that says, well, x actually was there,
而我呢？远离的？]它。
and I [? removed ?] it.
但你不应该在这个断言中隐藏删除调用，
But you should not bury that remove call in this assert,
因为如果断言被禁用，
because if assertions are disabled,
整个表达式不运行。
this entire expression doesn't run.
而x从未从列表中删除。
And x is never removed from the list.
你得改成这样写。
You have to write it like this instead. .
也就是说，打个电话把它移走，然后
That is, make your call to remove, and then
断言找到的变量。
assert the found variable.